Sosuke Nishikawa

MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER

📞 090-4161-7403 | 🖂 sosuken115@gmail.com | 🏕 sosuke115.github.io | 🗘 Sosuke115 | in sosuke-nishikawa-2100581a0 | 💆 @ponyo_ponyo115

Personal Profile Statement

A master's student at the University of Tokyo with experience in software and machine learning. Skilled at operating in a wide range of platforms and programming. Praised for the ability to work hard and to achieve goals. Currently studying natural language processing using deep learning.

Education

- Master's student in Information Science and Technology, The University of Tokyo, Echizen lab. Apr. 2020 Mar.
 2022 (Expected graduation)
- B.E. in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, The University of Tokyo, Tsuruoka lab. Mar. 2020, GPA: 3.8/4.2

Work and Research Experience _____

Echizen Lab, National Institute of Informatics

Tokyo, Japan Apr. 2020 - PRESENT

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

· Research fake news and biased news

Studio Ousia Tokyo, Japan

RESEARCH ENGINEER (PART TIME) Feb. 2020 - PRESENT

• Research multilingual models

SONY Tokyo, Japan

RESEARCH ENGINEER INTERN

Sep. 2020 - Oct. 2020

Sep. 2020 - Sep. 2020

• Research on dialogue systems

Cookpad Inc.

Tokyo, Japan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

• developmented the API that predicts ingredients from recipes

Wantedly Inc.

Tokyo, Japan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

Aug. 2020 - Aug. 2020

· developmented the model that recommends connections using graph embeddings

Stockmark Inc.
Tokyo, Japan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER (PART TIME)

Dec. 2018 - Dec. 2019

• Created web application that allows users to understand at a glance who is familiar with which fields

Publication

Analysis of bilingual word embeddings using pseudo corpus generated from Unsupervised Machine Translation

- NLP2020 (Japan)
- Sosuke Nishikawa, Yoshimasa Tsuruoka

Data Augmentation for Learning Bilingual Word Embeddings with Unsupervised Machine Translation

- · arXiv preprint
- Sosuke Nishikawa, Ryokan Ri and Yoshimasa Tsuruoka

Studio Ousia at the NTCIR-15 SHINRA2020-ML Task

- 15th NTCIR Conference
- Sosuke Nishikawa, Ikuya Yamada

Award _____

JGC-S scholarship foundation

Scholarship for study abroad program.

Competences _____

Languages Japanese (native), English (conversant, IELTS 6.0)

Programming Python, JavaScript/TypeScript, d3.js, Ruby, C/C++, ŁTFX, HTML/CSS, MySQL, Google Apps Script

Libraries Pytorch, Chainer, Tensorflow, Docker

Competitive prog. Atcoder sosuke115 (rate 1003)